[upbeat dramatic music]
[欢快的戏剧音乐]
*
- The Aquaphone, the
Mermalair's telecommunication
- 水听器，
Mermalair 的电信
device connecting city hall
连接市政厅的设备
with the underwater
crime-fighting
与水下的
打击犯罪
hero,
Mermaid Man.
英雄，
美人鱼男.
- Yello?
- 耶罗？
- Never mind.
It's just this idiot.
- 没关系。
就是这个白痴而已。
- Argh!
- 啊啊！
- By the power of Neptune...
- 凭借海王星的力量...
both: Mermaid
Man and Barnacle Boy unite!
两者：美人鱼
男人和藤壶男孩联合起来！
- To the invisible boatmobile.
- 到隐形的移动船。
- Yay.
- 耶。
[both imitating engine revving]
[两者都模仿发动机转速]
- This must be the secret lair
of an evil villain.
- 这一定是秘密巢穴
一个邪恶的恶棍。
- You're right.
- 你说得对。
- Wah-ha!
- 哇哈！
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- [giggling]
- [咯咯笑]
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
- Oh!
- 哦！
Looks like there's evil afoot.
看来有邪恶在作祟。
- And littering is a crime.
- What?
- 乱扔垃圾是犯罪行为。
- 什么？
I thought I had my house
sponge-and-star-proofed.
我以为我有我的房子
海绵和星星防护。
- Hey, Squidward, want to play
Mermaid Man
- 嘿，章鱼哥，想玩吗
人鱼男
and Barnacle Boy with us?
藤壶男孩和我们在一起吗？
- No!
- 不！
Now, please fall and get
seriously hurt.
现在，请跌倒并获得
严重受伤。
both: Ahh!
两人：啊！
- Ugh! Oof!
- 呃！钱币！
- I'm sure I've heard that "no"
before.
- 我确信我听到过“不”
之前。
- Holy something, Mermaid Man.
You can't mean--
- 神圣的东西，美人鱼男人。
你不可能是说——
- Yes, my young, pink ward.
- 是的，我年轻的粉红色病房。
It's none other than...
不是别人，正是...
Doctor Negative.
医生阴性。
- * I hate SpongeBob, and I hate
Patrick *
- * 我讨厌海绵宝宝，我也讨厌
帕特里克*
- It's that denying desperado's
siren song.
- 这就是否认亡命之徒的
海妖之歌。
- * Loathing SpongeBob, scorning
Patrick la-la-la-la-la-la *
- * 厌恶海绵宝宝，蔑视
帕特里克啦啦啦啦啦啦啦*
- He's obviously raising an army
of mutant vegetables.
- 他显然正在组建一支军队
突变蔬菜。
And that song he's singing...
还有他唱的那首歌...
both: Will bring them to life.
两者：将使它们栩栩如生。
- [whistling]
- [吹口哨]
both: Hyah!
两人：哈！
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
Although our foes were evil,
尽管我们的敌人是邪恶的，
their nutrition did not go to
waste, Doctor Negative.
他们的营养没有去
浪费，阴性医生。
- We're watching you.
- 我们正在看着你。
- That's it!
- 就是这样！
I'm gonna clobber you two!
我要打倒你们两个！
- Hey, Squidward, do you hear
that?
- 嘿，章鱼哥，你听到了吗
那个？
[whistle blowing]
[吹口哨]
You better hurry up or you'll be
late for work.
你最好快点，否则你会
上班迟到了。
- Yeah, you better do something
or whatever.
- 是的，你最好做点什么
或其他什么。
- [groaning]
- [呻吟]
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
Ohh.
哦。
- Ahh-ahh-ahh!
- 啊啊啊啊！
- * Mermaid Man, our hero
Barnacle Boy, you too *
- * 美人鱼人，我们的英雄
藤壶男孩，你也是*
- * Mermaid Man, crime-fighter
Barnacle Boy, makes do *
- * 美人鱼人，犯罪斗士
藤壶男孩，凑合*
- * Evil found its match today
- * 邪恶今天找到了对手
* Underwater justice and fair
play *
* 水下正义与公平
玩*
both: *Super plan, garbage can,
minivan, Mermaid Man *
两者：*超级计划，垃圾桶，
小型货车、美人鱼人 *
- Ahh!
- 啊！
Will you two shut up about that
stupid show?
你们两个能闭嘴吗
愚蠢的表演？
- Oh, did you say something
negative, Doctor Negative?
-哦，你说了什么吗
阴性，医生阴性？
- What the--how did--
- 什么--怎么做--
- I heard him say something
negative.
- 我听到他说了些什么
消极的。
[toilet flushing]
[冲厕所]
- Mermaid Man, that injured
victim's bandages
- 受伤的人鱼男
受害者的绷带
have come undone.
已经被撤销了。
- That poor man needs aid...
- 那个可怜的人需要援助......
of the first variety.
第一个品种的。
- [gasps]
- [喘气]
- Oh,
we forgot the peroxide.
- 哦，
我们忘记了过氧化物。
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
- That should hold you until the
surgeons
- 这应该能支撑你直到
外科医生
can amputate your torso.
可以截肢你的躯干。
- Hmmph.
[mumbling]
- 哼。
[咕哝]
both: Justice restored!
两人：正义恢复！
- Hey, super dorks, your turn to
take out the garbage.
- 嘿，超级傻瓜，轮到你了
把垃圾倒掉。
- All right, Dr. Negative, we'll
play
- 好吧，阴性博士，我们会
玩
along and take it out.
并把它拿出来。
Hiyah!
嗨！
- [gasps]
- [喘气]
Why are all my tables
empty?
为什么我所有的桌子都是
空？
Why am I not making money?
为什么我不赚钱？
- Because these two costumed
creeps chased them out.
- 因为这两个人穿着戏服
怪物把他们赶了出去。
[both grunting]
[两人都咕哝着]
- Oh. Mr. Squidward, step into
me office.
- 哦。章鱼哥先生，介入
我的办公室。
- Uh-oh, Patrick.
- 呃哦，帕特里克。
I think we got Squidward in
trouble.
我想我们把章鱼哥带进来了
麻烦。
- I'm gonna share a secret with
you that I never told anyone.
- 我要与人分享一个秘密
你我从来没有告诉过任何人。
- Uh, that's okay.
I don't need to hear a...
- 呃，没关系。
我不需要听...
Hmm?
唔？
- Ha! Ha-ha.
You're a comic book geek.
- 哈！哈哈。
你是一个漫画书迷。
- Ahh!
- 啊！
Don't touch those.
不要碰那些。
They're mint condition,
worth a fortune.
它们状况完好，
值一大笔钱。
- So you read comics.
Don't worry.
- 所以你看漫画。
不用担心。
Lots of perfectly immature
adults read comics.
很多完全不成熟
大人看漫画。
- Oh, it's deeper than that.
- 哦，比那更深。
I sewed it meself.
我自己缝的。
It's Captain
Tightwad from issue 53.
是队长
来自第53期的吝啬鬼。
They say he's a bad guy, but,
you know,
他们说他是个坏人，但是，
你知道，
I think he's just
misunderstood.
我认为他只是
误解了。
- Oh, look at that.
I think I left my oven on.
- 哦，看看那个。
我想我没关烤箱。
- I had some fabric left over,
so I made this.
- 我还剩下一些布料，
所以我做了这个。
- Oh, don't tell me...
Doctor Negative?
- 哦，别告诉我...
医生阴性？
- Ahoy, you high-sea halfwits.
- 哎呀，你们这些白痴。
[both gasp]
[两人都喘气]
- Tremble before Captain
Tightwad!
- 在队长面前颤抖
紧绷！
Squidward.
章鱼哥。
- And cower in fear of Doctor
Negative.
- 因害怕医生而畏缩
阴性。
- Holy shrimp.
- 圣虾。
This is the best day of my life.
这是我一生中最美好的一天。
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
*
both: Whoa! Oh!
两人：哇！哦！
Whoa-ho! Whoa!
哇哦！哇！
*
- What're you waiting for?
- Augh!
- 你还在等什么？
- 啊啊！
Ugh!
啊!
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
Ugh! Ow! Ow!
啊!噢！噢！
[both grunting]
[两人都咕哝着]
- Hyahhh!
- 哈啊！
- Why are we fighting Captain
Tightwad?
- 为什么我们要和队长战斗
吝啬？
He didn't even commit a
crime.
他甚至没有犯
犯罪。
- What--what do you mean?
- 什么-什么意思？
- Oh, Mr. Krabs, it's right here
in
-哦，蟹老板，就在这里
在
"Mermaid Man" number 98.
《人鱼男》98号。
"No superhero shall fight a
super villain
“任何超级英雄都不会与
超级恶棍
until that super villain
has committed a crime."
直到那个超级反派
已经犯罪了。”
- Uh...well...hey.
- 呃...好吧...嘿。
Ha-ha, see?
哈哈，看到了吗？
I just stole some money.
我只是偷了一些钱。
- Well, it's not really stealing
if it's your own money.
- 嗯，这并不是真正的偷窃
如果是你自己的钱。
- Oh, come on.
- 哦，来吧。
What do--what do I have to do
here?
What do——我必须做什么
在这里？
- Ahh-ahh-ahh!
- 啊啊啊啊！
- Are you sure about this?
- 你确定吗？
Isn't robbing a bank against the
law?
抢银行不是针对
法律？
- Well, yes, Mr. Krabs, but
you're not really
- 嗯，是的，蟹老板，但是
你不是真的
robbing a bank.
You're just pretending to.
抢劫银行。
你只是假装而已。
- And then we can play?
- Yep.
- 然后我们就可以玩了？
- 是的。
- Oh, okay.
- 哦好的。
Ahoy.
哎呀。
Anyone home?
有人在家吗？
It's Captain
Tightwad and Doctor Negative.
是队长
吝啬鬼和阴性医生。
We're
here to rob you.
我们是
来这里抢劫你。
Anyone here?
Hello?
这里有人吗？
你好？
- [snoring]
- [打鼾]
Barnacled nickels.
藤壶镍币。
Can I
help you ladies?
我可以吗
女士们，有帮助吗？
- Oh, yeah, thanks, old-timer.
=> - 哦，是的，谢谢，老前辈。
Um, we're pretending to rob this
bank.
嗯，我们假装抢劫这个
银行。
Where's the tellers?
Where's the money?
出纳员在哪里？
钱在哪里？
- Ain't no tellers.
- 没有出纳员。
ATM's outside.
自动提款机就在外面。
both: Heh-heh-heh-heh.
两人：呵呵呵呵。
- Aw, barnacles.
I forgot me debit card.
- 噢，藤壶。
我忘记带借记卡了。
- Wait a minute.
- 等一下。
I don't care if you
are ladies.
我不在乎你是否
是女士们。
Nobody pretends to rob
my bank.
没有人假装抢劫
我的银行。
- [roars]
- Ahh!
- [咆哮]
- 啊！
- Ahh!
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
Ow!
噢！
Ehh...
呃...
- [mumbling]
- [咕哝]
- Whoa, you were so convincing.
- 哇，你太有说服力了。
You
had that guard totally fooled.
你
那个守卫完全被愚弄了。
I think we can skip to the end
of the story.
我想我们可以跳到最后
的故事。
Let's just stop here to pick
up some props
让我们在这里停下来挑选
一些道具
for your evil lair.
为了你邪恶的巢穴。
We'll just need a few dollars...
yoink!
我们只需要几块钱...
哎哟！
- I'm supposed to be the
villain,
- 我应该是
恶棍,
so why do I feel like I'm being
robbed?
那么为什么我觉得我正在
抢劫？
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
- Okay Captain Tightwad...
- 好的，吝啬鬼船长...
Doctor
Negative, you can come out now.
医生
否定的，你现在可以出来了。
[cash register dings]
[收银机叮叮声]
both: Ahh!
两人：啊！
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
- Okay, so here's the scene.
- 好吧，这就是场景。
You two have us here in this
cage over a pool of boiling oil.
你们两个让我们在这里
笼子放在一池沸腾的油上。
Now, that is a
crime.
现在，那是一个
犯罪。
Now you can let us out so we
can fight.
现在你可以让我们出去了所以我们
可以战斗。
- Oh, I don't think we're going
to do that.
- 哦，我想我们不会去
这样做。
- Hey, wha-wha-wha-what are you
doing?
- 嘿，哇，哇，哇，你是谁
在做什么？
- Being evil.
- 作恶。
Isn't that what you wanted?
这不是你想要的吗？
Aren't you scared?
你不害怕吗？
Boo-hoo?
号泣？
- Boo-hoo?
Do you expect us to cry?
- 嘘？
你希望我们哭吗？
- No, Mr. Bob.
- 不，鲍勃先生。
I expect you to fry.
我期待着你去炒。
[laughs]
[笑]
- [laughs]
- [笑]
Ha-ha, ha-ha, hmm.
哈哈哈哈哈哈，嗯。
Okay, Squidward,
playtime's over.
好吧，章鱼哥，
游戏时间结束了。
This is getting a
little intense here.
这是得到一个
这里有点激烈。
- Too long have I suffered
living between you two ninnies.
-我受苦太久了
住在你们两个傻瓜中间。
But now--
now as Doctor Negative,
但现在——
现在作为阴性医生，
I shall finally exact my
exquisite revenge!
我最终将准确地表达我的
绝妙的复仇！
[laughs]
[笑]
[both chuckling]
[两人都笑了]
- See, I just knew he'd make a
terrific bad guy.
- 看吧，我就知道他会做一个
了不起的坏人。
He is really
committing.
他真的是
承诺。
- Yeah, you did a great job with
casting.
- 是的，你做得很好
铸造。
- Could this be end of our
Doofus Duo?
- 这会是我们的结束吗
杜福斯二人组？
Deep-fried like two tenacious
tater tots on tenterhooks?
炸得像两条顽强的
土豆泥们提心吊胆吗？
- Swing, Boy Under.
Swing the basket.
- 摇摆，下面的男孩。
晃动篮子。
[both grunting]
[两人都咕哝着]
both: Ahh-ahh-ahh-ahh.
两人：啊啊啊啊啊啊。
Ahhh!
啊啊！
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
*
- Oh, boy, Mr. Krabs.
- 哦，天哪，蟹老板。
That was the best Mermaid Man
playdate ever.
那是最好的人鱼男
永远的玩耍约会。
- Yeah, not bad.
- 是的，还不错。
But next time, we
won't go so easy on ya.
但下一次，我们
不会对你那么容易的。
- Eh...
maybe I'll just stick to
- 呃...
也许我会坚持
reading comics from now on.
从现在开始看漫画。
both: To the Mermalair!
两人：前往美马拉尔！
Ahh...oof!
啊……噢！
- And so ends another
numskulled episode
- 另一个就这样结束了
愚蠢的情节
of that preposterous pair:
那对荒谬的人：
Mermaid Pants and Barnacle
Star.
美人鱼裤和藤壶
明星。
Tune in next time for more
mind-rotting adventures.
下次记得关注更多内容
令人心碎的冒险。
I've really got to find another
job.
我真的必须再找一个
工作。
I wonder if it's too late to
go back to college radio?
我想知道现在是否太晚了
回到大学广播电台？